Guide to the Daniel Rubin Papers TAM.657
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series I: Communist Party National Organizational Bureau and Department, 1930-1991; 47 Linear Feet in 74 manuscript boxes, 9 record cartons, 1 half manuscript box and 6 cassette boxes; 145 audiocassettes
  - Subseries I.A: General Files, 1930-1991; 26 Linear Feet in 28 manuscript boxes, 4 record cartons, 1 half manuscript box, and 6 cassette boxes; 108 audiocassettes
    - Manuscripts of Other Party Members, 1985-1989 (Box 21, Folder 4-5)
    - Marti, Jose on Civil War in Chicago, 1986-1987 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Meiklejohn Civil Liberties Library Microfilm Catalog, 1969-1970 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Memorabilia: Buttons and Lapel Pins, 1930-2014 (Box 232, Folder 1-5)
    - Memorabilia: Cufflinks and Money Clip, undated (Box 218, Folder 6)
    - Memorabilia: The Old Agitator by Eliot Kenin, 1997 (Box 241, Cd 1)
    - Memorabilia: Pins, undated (Box 218, Folder 7)
    - Memorabilia: Stickers, undated (Box 218, Folder 8)
    - Met Council #30, undated (Box 238, Cassette 187)
    - Mexican-American: Chicano Liberation, 1971-1974 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Mexican-American Workshop I, undated (Box 234, Cassette 38)
    - Mexican-American Writings and Research, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Mexican Number 5, 1969-1970 (Box 22, Folder 2-3)
    - Music Scores, undated (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - National Alliance Against Racist and Political Repression, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - National Groups, 1966-1972 (Box 220, Folder 5)
    - National Organization Department, 1971 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - National Organization Department: General Files, 1983-1991 (Box 22, Folder 7-10)
    - National Organization Department: General Files, 1981-1983 (Box 23, Folder 1-8)
    - National Organization Department: General Files, 1969-1981 (Box 24, Folder 1-9)
    - National Organization Department: General Plan of Work, 1987 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - National Organization Department: Memoranda, 1981-1989 (Box 25, Folder 1-5)
    - National Organization Department: People's Daily World, 1986 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - National Organization Department: Spanish Report, undated (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - National Organizational Secretary: Correspondence: Barnes, Jim, 1971 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - National Organizational Secretary: Correspondence: Commission of Indian Liberation, 1971 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - National Organizational Secretary: Correspondence: General, 1970-1971 (Box 220, Folder 7-8)
    - National Organizational Secretary: Correspondence: General, 1970-1971 (Box 26, Folder 3-9)
    - National Organizational Secretary: Correspondence: General, 1971-1974 (Box 27, Folder 1-3)
    - National Organizational Secretary: Notebooks, 1974 (Box 220, Folder 9-10)
    - National Lawyers Guild Publications, 1969 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - National Question Research, 1986 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - National Rank and File Conference, 1970 (Box 220, Folder 11)
    - New Left, 1971, undated (Box 27, Folder 6-7)
    - New Outlook, 1967-1973 (Box 27, Folder 8-9)
    - New York Action, 1975 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - New York on Soviets, 1990 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - New York Team: Ken Question and Answer, 1978 November 30 (Box 236, Cassette 107-108)
    - Nixon and Watergate and Impeachment, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Notes on the Role of Clubs, 1972-1974 (Box 220, Folder 12)
    - Nuclear Energy, 1980 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Nuclear Energy: 22nd Convention, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Occupational Health and Disease: Chicago Lecture and Discussion, undated (Box 238, Cassette 188)
    - Office Equipment, 1967 (Box 220, Folder 13)
    - Organization Bureau: Notebooks, 1970-1971 (Box 220, Folder 14)
    - Organization Bureau, 1980-1981 (Box 28, Folder 1-4)
    - Organization Bureau: Meeting Minutes, 1968-1977 (Box 28, Folder 5-7, Box 234, Cassette 220-221)
    - Organization Bureau: Minutes, 1971-1974 (Box 220, Folder 15-16)
    - Organization Bureau: Old Records of Reference for Meetings, 1971-1975 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Organization Bureau: Notebooks, 1979 (Box 220, Folder 17)
    - Organization Bureau: Notes and Correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 220, Folder 18-19)
    - Organization Department: Assorted Notes, 1968-1970 (Box 220, Folder 20)
    - Organization Department: Miscellaneous, 1970-1976 (Box 220, Folder 21-22)
    - Organization Report, 1966 (Box 220, Folder 23)
    - Organization Report, 1966 (Box 221, Folder 1)
    - Other Communist Parties, 1960s (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Other Oppressed Peoples, Ideological Conference, 1989 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Pamphlets: Jobs, Peace, and Equality, 1982-1985 (Box 239, Folder 1)
    - Pamphlets: Marxism and Communism in the World, 1963-1982 (Box 239, Folder 2)
    - Pamphlets: Party Building, 1982-1985 (Box 239, Folder 3)
    - Pamphlets: US Politics, 1981-1988 (Box 239, Folder 4)
    - Party Affairs, 1967 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Passports, 1967 (Box 29, Folder 4-5)
    - Peace, 1970-1972 (Box 221, Folder 2-3)
    - Peace: Notes and Outlines, circa 1970s (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Peace Summit, 1981-1985 (Box 29, Folder 7-8)
    - Peace Summit: Iceland, 1986 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Peace: Cuba, 1990 (Box 29, Folder 10-11)
    - People's Daily World Articles, 1990-1991 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - People's World, 1970-1972 (Box 221, Folder 4)
    - Perlo Super Profits and Crisel, 1987 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Personal: Correspondence, 1976 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Personal Keepsakes: CPUSA, 1949-1994 (Box 30, Folder 2-5)
    - Phony Left (Incar Newsletter), 1989 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Plant Crossings Research, 1979-1980 (Box 30, Folder 7-8)
    - Poland, 1982 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Political: Collected Ephemera, 1985-1987 (Box 31, Folder 2-3)
    - Political Affairs, 1970 (Box 221, Folder 5)
    - Political Affairs, 1978-1984 (Box 31, Folder 4-7)
    - Political Bureau (P.B), 1986 January 28 (Box 237, Cassette 176)
    - Political Committee, 1970-1972 (Box 221, Folder 6-9)
    - Political Committee: Renewal of Organizational Bureau, 1971 (Box 221, Folder 10)
    - Posters, 1984-1986 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Printing Technique and Printers, circa 1982 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Puerto Rican Equality, undated (Box 234, Cassette 39-40)
    - Psychology and Marxism, 1964-1970 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Publications, 1972-1979 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Publications: Circulation and Subscriptions, 1967-1968 (Box 221, Folder 11-12)
    - Publications: Collected Statements by Gus Hall, 1981, 1989 (Box 239, Folder 5)
    - Publications: Left, 1942-1970 (Box 32, Folder 1-2)
    - Rand, Esther: Housing #32, circa 1980 (Box 235, Cassette 78)
    - Rand, Esther: #33, undated (Box 235, Cassette 79)
    - Rand, Esther: #60, undated (Box 235, Cassette 80)
    - Rand, Esther: #61, undated (Box 235, Cassette 81)
    - Recruiting, 1970-1973 (Box 32, Folder 3-6)
    - Recruiting, 1973, 1981 (Box 33, Folder 1-4)
    - Recruiting Brochure, etc., 1977 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Recruiting: Prior to 1981 (Box 33, Folder 6-7)
    - Registration: Party Membership, 1969-1970 (Box 221, Folder 13-14)
    - Registration Questionnaire, 1969 (Box 221, Folder 15)
    - Restaurants: Recreation, 1988 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Results Publications, 1980 February 16 (Box 237, Cassette 175)
    - Revisionism, undated (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Rosenbergs, 1983 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Rubin, Danny: Discussion, 1985 April 9 (Box 237, Cassette 143)
    - Rubin, Danny: Opening, Concludes, Discussion, 1985 April 9 (Box 237, Cassette 144)
    - Rubin, Danny: On Soviet Union, 1990 February (Box 238, Cassette 184)
    - Rubin, Dorothy: Spanish Language Articles and Language Practice, 1976 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Rubin to Gus Hall, 1989 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - "Safety and Health on the Job": Collected Articles from the Daily World, ed. Frank Carroll, 1976 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Secretariat: David Eisenhower, 1985 October 1 (Box 238, Cassette 189)
    - Secretariat Discussion: Minutes (notebook), 1964-1965 (Box 221, Folder 16-17)
    - Secretariat: Minutes, 1966-1968 (Box 221, Folder 18-20)
    - Settlers, 1990 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Schaffle, Mildred: Obituary, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Scientific and Technological Revolution, 1989 (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Second Half Reserved, undated (Box 238, Cassette 190)
    - Social Services in Today's Crisis Conditions: Conference Agenda, undated (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Steel Negotiations (National Labor and Organization Commission), 1988 (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Struggle for Women's Equality, undated (Box 233, Cassette 34-35)
    - Seniors: Stephanie Allen, undated (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Short Work Week, 1977-1978 (Box 34, Folder 13)
    - Socialist Countries, 1977-1978; 1989 (Box 34, Folder 14)
    - Socialist Countries: Renewing Ideology, 1987 (Box 34, Folder 15)
    - The Soviet Role in World War I, 1985 (Box 34, Folder 16)
    - Soviet Union: 27 Convention of the Communist Party of the Soviet Union, 1986 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - The State and Democracy, 1963 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Sterling Stuckey on Robeson, 1975 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Taxes Research, 1978 (Box 35, Folder 4-7)
    - Trade Union Conference: George Meyers, 1986 March 22 (Box 238, Cassette 186)
    - Trade Union and Workers, 1989-1991 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Transition to Socialism, undated (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Triple-Layered Crisis, 1985 (Box 35, Folder 10-11)
    - Tyner, Jarvis and Family, 2004 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Ultra-Right, 1969 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Unidentified: Tape I, 1985 November 19 (Box 237, Cassette 160)
    - Unidentified: Tape I: Side "A", 1986 May 6 (Box 237, Cassette 161)
    - Unidentified: Tape II, 1986 May 7 (Box 237, Cassette 162)
    - Unidentified: Tape III, 1986 May 8 (Box 237, Cassette 163)
    - Unidentified: Tape III, 1988 November 19 (Box 237, Cassette 170)
    - Unidentified: Tape #4, 1985 November 19 (Box 237, Cassette 180)
    - Unidentified: Paul re: WPL, undated (Box 237, Cassette 166)
    - Unidentified: Tape 2: Side 1, undated (Box 238, Cassette 195)
    - United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America Pamphlets, 1968-1972 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - USA Socialism Workshop Ideological Conference, 1989 (Box 234, Cassette 41-42)
    - USSR Economy of Capitalism, 1989 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - USSR: Russia Post-Break Up, 1993-2001 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - USSR Leaderships Reports, 1988 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - USSR Nationalities, undated (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - USSR Peace Fight, 1986 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Utility Coalition: Detroit, 1978 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Utilities Research, 1976-1978 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Utilities Research 2, 1976-1978 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Vacations, Sailorburg, 1980-1989 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Vacations: Bills and Pamphlets, 1990 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Vacations: Notes, Correspondence and Postcards, 1977-1980 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Vacations: Western Cape Town, 1989 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Vision 1199 Certificate, 1959-1963; 1990 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Voice Tape 2, 1974 October 3 (Box 238, Cassette 191)
    - Voice Tape Side 5, 1974 October 17 (Box 238, Cassette 192)
    - Watson, Joann, circa 1991 (Box 233, Cassette 9)
    - Weinstone, 1978 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Winston, Fern: Struggle for Women's Equality, undated (Box 238, Cassette 185)
    - Winston, Henry, Gus Hall, Commentary on Karl Marx / CPUSA on the Air, undated (Box 236, Cassette 109)
    - Winston, Henry: Speech at His 60th Birthday Celebration, 1971 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Winston Summary, undated (Box 236, Cassette 110)
    - Winston: continued, undated (Box 236, Cassette 111)
    - Working Class Workshop I: Ideological Conference, 1989 (Box 234, Cassette 43-44)
    - Working Class Workshop II, undated (Box 234, Cassette 45-46)
    - Workshop #5 Nationally Oppressed People, undated (Box 233, Cassette 47-48)
    - Workshop #8 Peace and Solidarity, undated (Box 234, Cassette 49-50)
    - Workshop #9 Global Problems, undated (Box 234, Cassette 51)
    - Workshop #10 Struggle for Democracy, undated (Box 234, Cassette 52-53)
    - Workshop #11 State and Government, undated (Box 234, Cassette 54-55)
    - Workshop #12 Cultural Arena, undated (Box 234, Cassette 56-57)
    - Workshop #14 US Socialism, 1989 (Box 234, Cassette 58)
    - Workshop #15 Developments in Socialist World, 1989 (Box 234, Cassette 59-60)
    - Workshop #16 The Party, undated (Box 234, Cassette 61-62)
    - Workshop #17 Reaching the Millions, undated (Box 233, Cassette 63-64)
    - World War II Articles, 1985 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - The Woman Question, 1991 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Women Strike for Peace Memos, 1967 (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - Women Strike for Peace: Park Slope, 1967-1968 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Working Families Party, 1999, 2000 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - World Marxist Review: Conference: Remarks by Henry Winston and James West, 1980 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - World Marxist Review: Publication Plan, 1981 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Writings, circa 1960s (Box 38, Folder 5-6)
    - Writings: Articles for Dialog, undated (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Writings on Self-Criticism, undated (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Writings: Other International Materials, 1964-1984 (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Writings: Published Article, 1959 (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - Writings: Public Statement on Being Supported By the Soviet Internal Security Committee, 1959 (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - Writings: Published or Distributed, 1964 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Subseries I.B: Clubs and Districts, 1959-1990; 10.75 Linear Feet in 10 manuscript boxes and 5 record cartons
    This subseries contains files documenting communication between the Communist Party's National Organization Department and local Party districts and clubs. Materials in this subseries include correspondence and statistics related to Party building, publication distribution, and recruitment activities of local Communist Party branches. New York and Eastern Pennsylvania districts are most well represented, and include notes and drafts of regional committee reports, leadership training seminars, and outlines for local workshops.
    Files in this subseries are arranged alphabetically by topic.
    - Alabama, 1969-1970 (Box 221, Folder 21)
    - Arizona: Arizona Worker, undated (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Brooklyn: Interview with Zita Fearon and Dorothy Rubin, 1973 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Brooklyn: Methodist Hospital, 1972 (Box 39, Folder 3-4)
    - Brooklyn: Neighborhood Map, undated (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Brooklyn Clubs: Park Slope, 1974 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - California, 1969-1973 (Box 221, Folder 22)
    - California, Northern, 1960 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - California, Northern, undated (Box 222, Folder 1)
    - California, Northern: Bulletins, 1980 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - California, Southern, 1960 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - California, Southern, 1966-1974 (Box 222, Folder 2-8)
    - California, Southern: Bulletins, 1976-1979 (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Classes for District and Club Cadre, 1989-1990 (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Club Draft, circa 1981 (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - Club Leadership, 1988 (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - Club Leadership, 1980-1982 (Box 222, Folder 9-12)
    - Club Leadership: Classes, 1988 (Box 222, Folder 13)
    - Club Leadership: Seminar, 1986-1988 (Box 222, Folder 14-16)
    - Club Manual, circa 1981 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Club Manual 2, circa 1981 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Club Manual Drafts, 1981 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Club Officers Handbook, 1946 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Club Outline, 1990 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Colorado, 1965 (Box 222, Folder 17)
    - Colorado Class, 1985 (Box 222, Folder 18)
    - Connecticut, 1966-1975 (Box 222, Folder 19)
    - Connecticut: Activity for Classes, 1989 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Connecticut: District Committee/Club Leadership, 1989 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Connecticut: District Committee, 1983 (Box 41, Folder 1-2)
    - Connecticut: Joelle Fishman: Congressional Candidacy, circa 1970s (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Connecticut: Teaching, 1989 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Communist Party Memos: Districts, 1968-1978 (Box 41, Folder 5-8)
    - District Program, 1983 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - District Committee: Notes and Resolutions, 1968 (Box 222, Folder 20)
    - District Education Activities, 1978-1982 (Box 222, Folder 21)
    - District Leadership Seminar, 1979-1980 (Box 222, Folder 22-23)
    - District Schools: Regional Outline Condensed, 1989-1990 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Districts: Publications Circulation, 1965-1967 (Box 222, Folder 24-28)
    - Districts: Publications Circulation, 1967-1972 (Box 223, Folder 1-7)
    - Districts: Publications and Recruitment, 1961 (Box 223, Folder 8)
    - Districts: Transfers, 1970 (Box 223, Folder 9)
    - Florida, 1965-1972 (Box 223, Folder 11-17)
    - Guide for Club Educational Program, 1988 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Hawaii, 1972 (Box 223, Folder 10)
    - Illinois, circa 1960 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Illinois, 1960-1973 (Box 223, Folder 18-22)
    - Illinois: Education and Organization, 1982 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Indiana, 1967-1972 (Box 223, Folder 23)
    - Indiana: Notes, 1970 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Juvenile Delinquency, 1960 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Kansas, 1971 (Box 223, Folder 24)
    - List of Trade Publications, 1967 (Box 223, Folder 25)
    - Local Activities, 1976-1978 (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Louisiana, 1973 (Box 223, Folder 26)
    - Main Report to the Convention of the California District of the Communist Party, 27544 (Box 224, Folder 1)
    - Maryland, circa 1960 (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Maryland, undated (Box 224, Folder 2)
    - Maryland and Washington D.C., 1966-1971 (Box 224, Folder 3)
    - Massachusetts: Laura Ross for Congress, 1984 (Box 240, Folder 5)
    - Michigan, 1960 (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - Michigan, 1970-1973 (Box 224, Folder 4)
    - Mid-West District, 1966 (Box 224, Folder 5)
    - Missouri, 1968 (Box 224, Folder 6)
    - Montana, undated (Box 224, Folder 7)
    - National Organizational Secretary: Correspondence on Districts and Clubs, 1967-1972 (Box 224, Folder 8-10)
    - National Organizational Secretary: Correspondence on Districts and Clubs, 1968-1977 (Box 42, Folder 11-13)
    - National Organizational Secretary: Correspondence on Districts and Clubs, 1971-1980 (Box 43, Folder 1-9)
    - National Organizational Secretary: Correspondence on Districts and Clubs: Alabama, 1970-1973 (Box 224, Folder 12)
    - National Organizational Secretary: Correspondence on Districts and Clubs: California, 1966-1973 (Box 224, Folder 13-20)
    - National Organizational Secretary: Correspondence on Districts and Clubs: Colorado, 1967-1972 (Box 224, Folder 21)
    - Newsletters and Bulletins: Clubs, 1971-1980 (Box 43, Folder 10-12)
    - Newsletters and Reports: Clubs, 1985-1991 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Newsletters: Districts, 1977-1980 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - New Jersey, 1960 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - New Jersey, circa 1980s (Box 224, Folder 23)
    - New Jersey: Club Leadership, 1985 (Box 224, Folder 24)
    - New Mexico, 1963-1967 (Box 224, Folder 25)
    - New York: Bulletins, 1973-1979 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - New York: Economy Indicators, 1975-1976 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - New York: Housing, 1970-1976 (Box 44, Folder 6-7)
    - New York: Outlook, 1975 (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - New York: Politics, 1974-1976 (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - New York: Social Conditions, 1975-1976 (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - New York Clubs: Leadership Training, 1980 (Box 224, Folder 27)
    - New York Clubs: Education, 1981 (Box 224, Folder 28)
    - New York Coalition to Fight Inflation and Unemployment, 1974-1975 (Box 224, Folder 26)
    - New York District 1, circa 1975 (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - New York District 1: Economic, 1977 (Box 44, Folder 12-13)
    - New York District 2, 1975 (Box 45, Folder 1-2)
    - New York District 3: Study Team, 1978 (Box 45, Folder 3-6)
    - New York District 4, 1984 (Box 45, Folder 7-8)
    - New York District 4, 1984 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - New York District 5, 1984-1989 (Box 46, Folder 2-6)
    - New York Districts, 1989 (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - New York Districts: November 16th Rally, 1974 (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - New York Districts, 1977-1978 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - New York Legislation, 1975 (Box 224, Folder 29)
    - New York Report: Administrative, 1989 (Box 224, Folder 30)
    - Notes and Reports on Districts, 1970s (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Ohio, 1960 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Ohio, 1969-1971 (Box 225, Folder 1)
    - Oklahoma, 1968-1969 (Box 225, Folder 2-3)
    - Oregon, 1968-1972 (Box 225, Folder 4)
    - Outline for Club: Perlo Book, 1988 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Outlines for Clubs, 1981-1986 (Box 47, Folder 5-8)
    - Park Slope Club, 1977 (Box 224, Folder 22)
    - Party School: East Pennsylvania, 1976 (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - Pennsylvania, Eastern, 1967-1972 (Box 225, Folder 6-8)
    - Pennsylvania, Eastern, 1987-1990 (Box 47, Folder 10-11)
    - Pennsylvania, Eastern, 1989-1990 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Pennsylvania, Eastern: Elections, 1984 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Pennsylvania, Eastern: FBI Reports on African American Groups, 1971 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Pennsylvania, Eastern: Political Action, 1954-1974 (Box 225, Folder 9)
    - Pennsylvania, Western: Lecture, 1970-1972 (Box 225, Folder 10)
    - Pennsylvania, Western: Leadership, 1966-1968 (Box 225, Folder 11)
    - Pennsylvania, Western: Women's Peace Activism, 1982-1983 (Box 48, Folder 4-5)
    - Pennsylvania: United Steelworkers of America Handbook, undated (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Philadelphia and Washington D.C., 1979 (Box 225, Folder 12)
    - Plan of Work: On Role of Clubs, 1975 (Box 225, Folder 13)
    - Report to the Southern California District Members, 1975 (Box 225, Folder 14)
    - State and Club Leadership, 1989-1990 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - South, 1960 (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - South, 1963-1971 (Box 225, Folder 15-16)
    - Tennessee, 1967 (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - Texas, 1966-1972 (Box 225, Folder 17-22)
    - Texas: Correspondence, 1966 (Box 225, Folder 23)
    - Utah, 1967 (Box 225, Folder 24-25)
    - Washington, 1966-1973 (Box 225, Folder 26)
    - Washington and Idaho, undated (Box 225, Folder 27)
    - Washington D.C.: District Leadership, undated (Box 225, Folder 28)
    - Wisconsin, undated (Box 225, Folder 28)
    - Wisconsin and Minnesota, 1960 (Box 48, Folder 10)
    - Wisconsin and Ohio: Education and Organization, 1980 (Box 48, Folder 11)
    - West Virginia, undated (Box 225, Folder 30-31)
  - Subseries I.C: Conventions, 1955-1991; 7.5 Linear Feet in 15 manuscript boxes and 1 record carton
    This subseries documents Communist Party National Conventions, beginning with the 16th National Convention in 1955 and ending with the 25th National Convention in 1991. Other conferences documented in this series include the 1962 Special Convention, the 1982 Extraordinary Conference, the 1989 Ideological Conference, and several other topical conferences. Files on conferences include discussion bulletins, committee reports, draft resolutions, notes and outlines for workshops on various discussion topics, notes from meetings.
    Files in this subseries are arranged alphabetically by convention or conference title.
    - Convention, 16th: Discussion Bulletins, 1955 (Box 48, Folder 11-13)
    - Convention, 16th: Discussion Bulletins, 1955 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Convention, 16th: Pennsylvania in Facts and Figures, 1955 (Box 49, Folder 2-3)
    - Convention, 17th: Resolutions, 1959 (Box 49, Folder 4-7)
    - Convention, 18th: Convention Finances, Transport, Report, 1966 (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Convention, 18th: Discussion Bulletins, 1966 (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - Convention, 18th: Discussion Bulletins, 1966 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Convention, 18th: Reports and Resolutions, 1966 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Convention, 18th: Resolutions, 1966 (Box 50, Folder 3-4)
    - Convention, 18th: Resolutions Party Organization, 1966 (Box 50, Folder 5)